

Nguyen Van Binh

Solution Architect / Technical Leader / Front-End Developer

Profile Summary

I'm a passionate front-end developer more than 8 years of experience. Focus on development for web, desktop, mobile and devices. I have worked with different programming languages, javascript libraries, and frameworks.

I have worked in different environments, in international and in local teams, for different clients in different countries as well.

Specialties: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Angular, jQuery, Responsible Websites, Usability. I also like: Node JS, Site Performance.

Experience

Front-End Solution Arc	hitect/Technical Le	eader
FPT Software		
Sep 2017 - Present		
Sep 2017 – Present	Responsibilities	 Analyze customer functional and technical requirements and propose the most suitable front end strategy for frameworks and tools to be used Create Proof of Concepts\Prototypes for exemplifying the implementation for the front end team Define the technical guidelines and best practices in projects Be up to date with the latest front end related technologies and share the findings with the groups interested Coach\Mentor\Training Developers Implement code Languages & Technologies: Angularjs, Angular Typescript, React, Webpack, SASS, LESS
Front-End Developer		
Match Move		
Jul 2015 – Jul 2017 (2		
years)		
July 2015 – July 2017	Project Technologies	Mobile Wallet & Payment Cards MatchMove Pay is a financial technology company that provides innovative, end-to-end enterprise payment solutions. Offer secure mobile wallet solution that includes P2P transfer, Remittance, Top Up channels, Virtual Payment Cards, Loyalty Points & Rewards, Promotions & Offers amongst many other features. • Languages & Technologies: Angular, Angular Material, Meteor, SASS, LESS, Bootstrap, Node JS, Git, Grunt, Gulp

Front-End Technical Le	ader	
SmartOSC		
Nov 2014 - Jul 2015 (9 mg	nths)	
100 2014 - Jul 2015 (9 IIIC	<u> </u>	a Commence annicate CMC magainte
	Project Responsibilities	eCommerce projects, CMS magento
	Responsibilities	Tracking the project's progress. Discuss to project manager for
November 2014 - July		any issues in deadline and project's budget
2015		Do code review for members in the team
		 Tracking the code quality and developer's skill
		Training
Senior Front-End Deve	loper/Group Leade	r
Lazada Group		
June 2013 - November 20	14 (1 year 6 months)	
June 2013 – November	Project	Online Shopping Lazada
2014		The Southeast Asian online retailer often compared to Amazon,
		for instance. The website uses a self-development CMS same
		same as Magento based on PHP language.
	Responsibilities	
	Responsibilities	Build and maintain features in lazada website for 6 ventures in
		SCRUM and KANBAN
		 Project lead for some features and support other members in
		development.
		Communicate with PMs, team leads, QA to clarify requirements.
		requirements.Take the role group leader in the big feature.
		Take the role group leader in the big reature.
	Technologies	 Backbone, jQuery, Angular, SASS, LESS, Mustache, Bootstrap, Node JS, Git, PHP, Linux OS, Grunt, Gulp, NPM, Brewhome
Senior Front-End Deve	loper / Web Develo	
Axon Active Vietnam		
October 2012 – June 2013	3 (9 months)	
October 2012 – June	Project	Business4you
2013		Build and maintain marketing websites for Switzerland market.
2013	Responsibilities	band and maintain marketing websites for switzerland market.
	Responsibilities	Build new websites and maintaining old websites using Typo3
		 Joining in all steps to develop a new website in SCRUM
		 Support other members.
		 Train other members in the front-end team.
	Technologies	
Coffee Francisco I Co		FE languages, Phonegap, RWD, Typo3, Magento
Software Engineer / Se		eloper
Harvey Nash Company		
April 2010 – October 2013		
Senior Front-End	Project	Hearst Magazine Digital Media
Developer		A unit of Hearst magazines, is dedicated to creating and
March 2011 – October		implementing the digital strategy for Hearst's magazine brands
2012		and other sites such as Cosmopolitan, Good Housekeeping,
		Harper's Bazaar.
	Responsibilities	
		Maintaining the web-applications.
		Research and present new technologies. Troubleshoot diagnose, and resolve complex technical issues.
		Troubleshoot, diagnose, and resolve complex technical issues.

esponsive
:sponsive
nagement
адеттетт
pt and
al issues.
t testing
n for
Sales
al issues.
i t

Additional Information

Education: 2004–2009: Bachelor/Information Technologies - University of Dalat, Dalat city, Vietnam.

Languages: Vietnamese (Mother tongue)

English (Upper-Intermediate)

Personal Information

Birthday: December 12th, 1986

Marital status: Married

Email: nguyenvanbinhctk28@gmail.com

Phone numbers: 0909 277 741

Address 8/7, Tan Chanh Hiep 16, ward Tan Chan Hiep, district 12, HCMC